e
you like what besides your family be
besides your children you know what
drives you to to be such a hard worker
sure yeah I mean obviously my why as you
said my faith in my family um and I
started to make a change in to to live
my why in life right um so I can live my
why as I become more successful I'll
also be building an amazing cause with
me as I'm successful but deep down deep
deep down you know I want to be super
successful because I was that little boy
no opportunity I didn't have any chance
in life but I was given an opportunity
and I ran with it you know I I didn't
have a father so I want to be the best
father possible I didn't have
um I necessarily have my my mother
either so I want to have a great family
life so like deep down The Roots the
Roots of my drive definitely comes from
my from you know not having my my mother
and my father as a kid and wanting to
make sure I excel first and foremost as
a father and as a husband and and to
build something so phenomenal for my
kids future that um it's it's almost you
know you can't break it I mean something
you tou talked about earlier when we're
talking about luck you know a lot of
people think that you know like let's
say like rich people like even Donald
Trump whoever um a lot of people might
be inheriting something or they might be
giving something but the thing is
that's what their father worked for you
know that's what those families have
worked for you know I'm working for my
future Generations I'm I'm working to
that my little Jo little JoJo and Ellie
and sah I'm working so that they have a
future and they can continue to build on
it and build on it welcome to the hustle
Zone can every I I I'm just seeing low
levels I don't know if people can hear
me can you hear me can you hear me
testing let me know if you guys can hear
me and uh I'm just testing the
mic uh I'm just getting really bad there
we go we got some good feedback there
okay so welcome to the hustle Zone it's
Ryan Perez AKA bowai creative
entrepreneur seral entrepreneur we got
um I I got a few businesses that are
going to be starting up pretty soon a
songwriting uh company and um a
production company which is doing all of
this right now it's the you know this is
the production company so we're going to
be doing more Productions so if you are
an entrepreneur or you have a crazy show
idea and you want it to be produced by
The Wonderful Wizard Productions then
you need to um message me in my DMs and
I'll be able to to to to help you out
you know we at least take a look at your
idea and see if we would we would
produce it so other other other things
uh the weight loss challenge I'm losing
weight I feel better I feel more energ
ized you know um but it's still like you
know watching those videos and then
going back and seeing those moves I just
want to get rid of those moves you know
like it's just it's just what needs to
happen all right but you know thank you
guys for your encouragement thank you
guys for the meal um plans and all that
stuff I've been taking it in and I've
been I just been going cold turkey and
just eating the best food ever and um it
feels great honest to God it just feels
great to be cuz again you don't want to
be an entrepreneur but you can't enjoy
it right you know today's guest I'll
tell you I want to be like him I want to
be able to do a live in a hot
tub right this guy does lives in a hot
tub he's just like he has his hands out
he's just like yo what's up he's just
chilling I want to be able to do that
you know but I can't do that until I get
rid of these moves right because I'll
probably get in trouble you know for
coming on live with those moves so I I
either way um enough of those I
um to kick to kick off this hustle Zone
today and I want to just welcome
everyone in the room I I can't see you
right now but I will in in a few minutes
um being a father I think is one of the
most important things I wanted to be an
entrepreneur because I just wanted to be
home with my child and when people would
ask me what did you want to be when you
grow up you know like I just wanted to
have a family I remember meeting my
son's mom and saying I just want like a
greenhouse I want a dojo and I want you
know I want to be home with my son and
that was my dream before Malcolm was
born so right now if people ask me are
you living your dream yes I'm living my
dream I get to be home with my children
or my child sorry I don't have children
but um
that that was the whole emphasis of of
being a father because I didn't have one
you know I didn't have an active father
I had a stepfather that is my father but
I had a biological father that I did not
know and um today's guest did not know
his
father you know
and on top of that there's again when
you guys watch The Hustle Zone The
Hustle zone is about the story leading
up to the glory it's just trying to
humanize the entrepreneur so that we get
a you know we understand that everyone
is the same or you know because a lot of
people think that they can't be
entrepreneurs because they have crappy
lives some parents do drugs and they're
like you know I was brought up in this
home and this home and I was in a group
home I can't be an entrepreneur and I'm
going to show you that every single one
of these entrepreneurs have a story
similar to yours the only difference is
that we have different habits and
everything that I just mentioned has
something to do with
Joshua and so he's come together and put
together a fantast he's what I call a uh
a social
entrepreneur right he's every day out
there grinding but for social causes he
has a book as well on how to make money
too
if you want to you know so and I would I
and if you if you want to be broke then
don't buy his book but if you want to
learn how to double your income and you
want to learn to change your life and to
spend time uh to be a great role model
for your children or if you don't have
children just to be in a better place
then you definitely want to buy his book
and so Joshua has definitely has a crazy
story but also has a Crazy Life now and
he's an he is an amazing father amazing
husband and um you know and he's a great
entrepreneur that you know a lot of
people follow him so I save me from
Rambling I'm GNA welcome Joshua theren
to the show how's it going my friend hey
what's going on brother Ryan thank you
so much for having me on the hustle Zone
today man I just want to touch on
something you said when I'm doing my hot
tub talks don't let me fool you you know
from the chest shoulders shoulder up
it's all good but man I got to do some
work
down down in the you know the good old
gut but you know it's all good but I
like the I love the hot tub you know
because it's just like what because you
know when we when we all started this
whole motivational thing Facebook live
we're just killing it on Facebook live
you know we just started this revolution
I think we on the we are on the edge of
this technology I think and yeah you
know you had Keenan white in the morning
waking you
up and he's out on the beach and then
you got Joshua at night you know he's
just
relaxing chill you hustling all day and
then you got Jonathan he's like hey
what's up what's up what's happening
what's happening what's happening so oh
go ahead I tell you what I was about to
bring the hot tub uh talk back but in
the winter time it gets real cold round
from gets down to zero so sometimes the
hot tub it's I'm not going to lie it's
one of those like like um vinyl hot tubs
so in the winter time it's hard to keep
up with the heat on it so I didn't want
to put it too much stress on it so I'll
try to bring it back in the spring wooo
well yeah man it's it's uh I think that
um either way I just want to say I I
really enjoy uh what you've done um and
you know you had a a not a launch party
but you had a Gala and I just remember
watching that and just seeing how
passionate you were about the youth and
you know me coming from a background
where it wasn't the greatest background
and you know but realizing that with my
story I was able to change uh youth's
lives you know I I would do speaking
engagements and stuff and I I can
identify where you were coming from you
know and you're you were you just put
your whole heart into it and you
everyone Embraces it because you're such
a great person you're a great guy so I'm
more than happy to have you on the
hustles on any time um and I just wanted
to get that out of the way I just think
I really like what you're doing man uh
so uh the first question that I normally
ask and people will get mad if I don't
ask it is what is your story my
friend well I'll start from the
beginning all right so I was a I was a
year and a half years old when I lost my
father he died at heroin overdose so I
never got to know my father at a young
age and the next few years I mean don't
get me wrong I've got some memories and
I could go into deeper de deep deep
details if I want to but you know long
story short you know I was I was made
fun of as a little kid you know I didn't
have much confidence um you know I
remember in third grade being told I
smell like Shi you know because I didn't
have good hygiene you know my mother she
struggled with substance abuse as well
so having gone through all that you know
I definitely know what it's like to
start from the bottom you know to start
from uh the hood so to speak and I was
blessed at 9 years old though to have my
aunt and uncle who rescued me from that
lifestyle you know they they took me in
as a little boy and they just started to
show me what love was they show they
they showed me what faith was through
Jesus and that's that's how I live my
life that's like my number one most
important part but you know they also
show me what love is as a kid they gave
me memories you know they they did what
they needed to do to change a little
boy's life and they did a good job at it
I gave them a lot of credit they're I
consider them some of my heroes um
especially my aunt you know my aunt's
actually uh she's an amazing woman and
she actually homeschooled me at seventh
grade on
and she had a um she has a heart
condition she was born with she almost
passed away actually when I was a junior
in high school and somehow she just went
through it and she she um she's still
here today and she's she's my mother
figure I consider her my mother figure
later on though After High School I gra
I went to college I went to Fitchburg
State University and I was a exercise
science major it's not doing me too good
right now but um and I did a minor in
business and while I was in college I
was a 19-year-old kid and I got the news
when I lost my
mother um my mother was I loved my mom
don't get me wrong you know I really
wanted to um I truly believed that I was
going to be the man that someday would
be able to be in her life and to help
make her change her ways you know and
hopefully show her the love that she
never was shown but I lost that
opportunity and she Haro and overdosed
it was actually six years ago January
15th so it was just a couple days ago um
the anniversary of it and I was crushed
man um but you know the first things
that came out of my mouth when I heard
that news was I say it every single time
I talk about it
God please don't let it be true and if
it is use me to be a vessel to change
people's lives in my story and I'm a big
you know I I consider my life motto uh
it's it's a Bible verse Romans 8:28 all
things work together for good to those
who love God you know I look at my past
I look at my my father my mother and I
see you know the bad things that have
happened in my personal life and I know
that it all is going to work out good
and and there's a purpose and a reason
for everything that happens in our
life and now later on that year I met my
wife um she was 17 years old at the time
she so I guess she's my high school
sweetheart even though I was in college
at the
time and um she's in amazing person man
I I I give my wife a lot of credit for
where we are as individuals and where I
am personally with my my business
success my nonprofit success without her
support I couldn't do it so um we were
we're getting married in 2014 June
2014 and um this is kind of a long story
short as well I can uh maybe Post in the
comments below later like the whole
testimony that you saw at the
garion um but we had opportunity to take
in my nieces my two nieces who I love
dearly and it was a crazy time in my
life I can't even like begin to put into
words what it was like we didn't live
together yet we were we were just about
to get married and then this opportunity
to be there from my two
nieces came on my plate and my wife's
plate and and we just made it happen we
just did it you know so in April 2014
the girls were in our house and we were
starting to take care of them and out of
nowhere we were just parents and then we
got married in June and then I became
sales agent in of insurance in July that
year and then I bought my first house in
October that year I mean everything just
boomed after that and um I credited a
lot of that you know to the faithfulness
and love of my wife and of course the
faith to just be able to willing to take
action and to keep going regardless and
and now um I'm a I'm a father of a a
third little boy his name is JoJo he's
their brother um
that they came back to our house in
March
2015 and they've been with us ever since
uh We've started a real estate
investment uh company where we like buy
and sell houses we we rehab we do rental
properties for passive income and in
June 2016 you I was sitting there and
and sometimes the real estate uh world
can be slow um especially early on in a
new business and I was just you know
like I said to myself with my friends
and my my family why why why not just
start living out our purpose now while
we while while we try to become
successful as well so something that I'm
a big believer in is what is your why in
life and my first and foremost why is of
course my faith and of then my family
you know those are the most important
things in my life but there was another
deeper thing that I wanted to start and
that was where make a change in came in
you know I believe that me and my wife
particular that our our call in this in
this life is to help change the kids of
lives who've been through what I've been
through what my kids are going through
and to be able to be the vessel used to
help make a change in their life and we
do that now at make a change Inc through
impactful meaningful memories and
education in particular faith in
financial education as an entrepreneur I
value you know the financial education
in so many different aspects and
different ways so that's something I
believe is important for the kids that
we're trying to impact at make Aang
in.org
mhm so that's where I'm at right now
well that's an amazing Story I mean um I
think
that uh the first thing that some people
may say well hey you got lucky you know
um and I'm not saying that like
specifically to you but you know that's
a lot of a lot of people have this
misconception that entrepreneurs are
lucky you know you got you you know you
worked at insurance and you got a good
job you paid for your house and you know
everything skyrocketed you're just you
know you you have privilege or whatever
it is it could be you know what would
what would your response be to
them uh luck is the last thing that that
allowed everything that happened in my
life to happen what it was was hard work
and determination period you know people
don't realize how much work and how much
even education and how much time goes
into what we do R you know starting up
businesses you know on top of that still
working out working and getting an
income being a father being a husband
like hard work and you know I I struggle
honestly having sympathy for people who
work just a little bit you know um
because I was a college kid when I when
I got engaged to my wife and at that
point in my life I said you know what
I'm dedicating my life to um to provide
for her and to build for my family going
forward so I started working literally
80 hours a week see back then I wasn't
an entrepreneur yet I didn't know like
different ways and better ways of
getting money so I just ramped up the
work and so I was working 80 hours a
week I I did five college classes
full-time college student and of course
I was a full-time uh fiance so and
honestly ever since that happened that
was in my junior year of uh College ever
since then it's been no different you
know today um I'm still working 80 to
100 hours a week I I still make time for
my family and that's what my life is
focused on is focused on building
helping people and helping my family as
well my kids so hard work is only way
that makes happen I think everyone would
say that you know you grant card don't
big guys they all say you know it's hard
work that don't make it nothing nothing
that we that we receive out of doing
what we do is luck how many what would
you say like um how many hours do you
spend a day on work like how like when
you say hard work like what does that
mean like what what's your what's your
regimen um when I wake up I start
working um and usually I'll be working
till about 5 or 6:00 just straight
working you know I'll take my break here
and there you know I'll have lunch and
I'll go to the gym or whatever but um
I'll spend time around dinner time with
my family for an hour and a half or so
um I'll read a book with them we'll pray
whatever we do um and then usually when
the kids go to bed me we go back at it
you know back to work from 8 8 till
about at this right now it's like 8:
till about 1:00 in the
morning that that I'm working so I'm
pretty much working and you know 12 15
14 hour days but I'm making sure that
I'm having my quality time with my
family in between all of this um but
when I say hard work you know it's not
just about like working physically hard
it's about um being willing to commit to
Growing whatever it is that you're doing
so in my situation you know I have to
make income for my family and then I
also have to continue to run nonprofit
with making Chang in which is like my
why my purpose in life and I still have
to focus on my long-term wealth which is
in my real estate
so when I say hard work I guess I'm
saying focusing hyperfocusing on your
responsibilities and making sure you get
what you got to get done day in and day
out so what D what really drives you
like what besides your family be besides
your children you know what drives you
to to be such a hard worker sure yeah I
mean obviously my why as you said my
faith in my family um and I started to
make a change Inc to to live my why in
life right um so I can live my why as I
become more successful I'll also be
building an amazing cause with me as I'm
successful but deep down deep deep down
you know I want to be super successful
because I was that little boy no
opportunity I didn't have any chance in
life but I was given an opportunity and
I ran with it you know I I didn't have a
father so I want to be the best father
possible I didn't have
um I necessarily have my my mother
either so I want to have a great family
life so like deep down The Roots the
Roots of my drive definitely comes from
my from you know not having my my mother
and my father as a kid and wanting to
make sure I excel first and foremost as
a father and as a husband and and to
build something so phenomenal for my
kids future that um it's it's almost you
know you can't break it I mean something
you tou talked about earlier when we're
talking about luck you know a lot of
people think that you know like let's
say like rich people like even Donald
Trump whoever um a lot of people might
be inheriting something or they might be
giving something but the thing
is that's what their father works for
you know that's what those families have
worked for you know I'm working for my
future Generations I'm I'm working to
that my little Jo a little JoJo and
Ellie and sah I'm working so that they
have a future and they can continue to
build on it and build on it and build on
it so you know generational wealth um is
super important to me and my deep root
to why I'm driven is because of my my
past my
childhood so uh let's touch let's touch
on the on on the on your childhood for a
bit you
know actually sorry before I go there I
wanted you you had mentioned about
losing your mom you know right around
right in the time where you're becoming
a man you know and how did you feel
during that time like how did you
internalize
that I mean to be honest for like I
don't even know how long ago was could
have been a year I felt like every
single day I was just in mourning I
wouldn't say depressed I would say just
in mourning and sadness that I can't be
there for her so to be honest
there's also a level of um I'll talk
about that actually in a minute but it
was sad and it was hard on me but I was
to fight through it to crush the odds
you I think of you know we all start
life off with a huge Rock and I'm just
and that's and that's our odds and I'm
just trying to crush it break it down
every day so that when I was going
through that time in my
life I just had to stay focused and
determined to what my future was and
what I was determined to be and that I
would not succumb
to what I could have easily become you
know I could have easily been the boy
who a drug dealer or um was living on
the streets that could have been my life
but you know I was blessed by God and
and when that when I was going through
that God honestly my faith was my
stronghold through it all and that's
that's how I was able to get through it
to be honest so when did you realize
that you know that because you know I
think that a lot of us for especially
for the people that we love we feel that
we're responsible somewhat for what
happened you know and when did you
realize that you weren't responsible for
what had happened to your
mom uh to be honest I never I never
really felt responsible I'm I'm 100% a
believer in choices to be straight
honest with you
um what I felt more
was that I just never got the
opportunity to to love her like I wanted
to and I and I and I put it because I
was only a boy you know I was just a
little boy when I was growing up and how
am I supposed to be a man I'm just a boy
you know so as I was growing up trying
to get to college I was trying to build
my foundation and build so that by the
time I was ready I could step in and be
there for my mother but you know I never
really honestly looked at me as the the
reason for it um something that I I
truly believe in and something that as I
teach my to never be bitter or something
um I always loved my mom regardless of
you know whether she could or couldn't
be a mother to me I loved her and I
that's what I teach my kids and that's
also what we want to teach our kids that
we impact at make a changeing yeah yeah
I just wanted to um interrupt here just
wanted to
say uh I just want to acknowledge
Richard thank you for for coming into
the broadcast Rich jinho yes and we got
Dave Dave body uh Leon P or Pearson we
have Henry my boy from Calgary
Carly we have Adam Parker oh it's nice
to see you Adam um we also have Patrick
Vanderbilt in here and then we got Mikey
Campbell so folks thank you guys all for
tuning in uh uh for the hustle Zone like
this is amazing every single time we do
this we get better audiences uh more
audiences coming in and we get more uh
engagement so I encourage you guys to
talk you know and to spread the word and
you know I never ask people to like or
share but if you do feel that you know
this content is worth going on your
timeline please kindly share um you know
this is an amazing story Joshua um I
think that you know you because you seem
like I think that a lot of us when we we
have a lot of us kids when we have
issues at home
uh we become more mature than our age
did you did you find that growing up did
you find that you you you were a little
bit more uh just wiser than a lot of the
people that you were hanging out with
absolutely I mean to be honest as a kid
as as a teenager you know especially
that's sometimes looked at as Rebellion
to be honest you know what I mean like
oh who does he think he is but you know
I knew what I had been going through at
that time my life and to I it was hard
especially as a kid for me to grasp that
I know I may have gone through more than
a lot of people so it's hard for me to
say yo you know more than me you know
better than me but you know now as an
adult it's so true man I mean look at
I'm living the life of like a
40-year-old I mean I got three kids a
wife a house you know um a career
businesses I mean when I go when I went
I went on a trip last year to Dubai it
was awesome went to Dubai India it was
like a cruise it was so much fun but man
everyone on the boat was like 60 70
years old and we were like relating with
them you know we were talking with them
we it's easy for me and my wife to have
a conversation with those who are older
than us you know most of the people that
we interact with they're in the 30s and
40s and 50s and we're only in our 20s
like young 20s too so it's definitely um
you know my life experience is
definitely
um you know
rapidly um grun my maturity you know so
it's funny I I look at maturity as this
maturity is not necessarily just like
how your outward app parents looks I
believe maturity is the actions you take
and the choices you make show and Define
what kind of maturity you have as an
individual so you know I'll be honest
you know Ryan when I'm just hanging out
with my I'm just with my wife D I'm
crazy and I'd be considered an immature
whack job but you know when it's time to
focus when it's time to get down to
business you know and making the right
choices um my life past has definitely
grown me and molded me to be the man I
am awesome so now tell me a little bit
about your
book my book oo look at this double in
nothing 2x your income in two years so I
wrote this book Because as a 25-year-old
you know I may not be a millionaire yet
I'm G to
be um but I know that I've done some
good things in life that and I and I I
know that I've heard some of the hate
you know who is he to do all these
things and like how is he doing it and
my book I wrote my book because I want
to show people the way and how they can
do it you know how can they live a more
fulfilling life how can they gain more
income and how they can use that income
to live a fulfilling life so um my
favorite chapter in the book is chapter
eight when I talk about your why you
know there's a lot of good contents in
here I talk about different seasons in
your life the importance of like getting
your money right through you know make
it you know Grant Cardone talks about
offens and defense so I talk about
making sure you get your money right so
you can just stay on say stay on offense
forward um and so there's some other
different topics in here but my favorite
is your why what is your why in life and
to me if you're looking to get more
money you're looking to become more
successful you're looking to maybe your
goals to be millionaire you have to make
sure it's surrounded and driven by a why
you know so my why in life you've
already know it by now my family my
faith and make a change and the kids
that I'm able to impact so I don't just
want to be a millionaire to have a
Rolls-Royce even though I do want a
Rolls-Royce someday I do like that car
but my real reason is because I'm driven
by true Joy of being able to impact kids
and to provide for my family awesome so
we're going to cut to commercial here
and uh we'll be back for the second line
of questioning so if you don't mind to
put yourself on mute my friend and uh
and then we'll uh get you
back a web design company in Calgary is
taking the concept of helping others to
a whole new level and as Robin Crawford
reports it was an Okanogan man who
inspired them to use their Tech skills
to help people with
disabilities it gives me great pleasure
to introduce to you Michael D Haynes a
motivational speaker an entrepreneur and
a businessman Michael Haynes is doing it
all and I absolutely love it it's the
best job I've ever had in the beginning
Haynes admits that he didn't know how to
get his customer service Consulting
business off the ground and then he met
Ryan Perez with both I creative for
every website that we sell we donate uh
free websites to entrepreneurs with
disabilities the Calgary based company
builds websites for businesses Haynes
knew he needed a website to promote
himself and Perez knew he had the tools
to help we were always talking about
working um um in the in or doing
something for the disability for the for
people with disabilities um but we
didn't know what we were going to do and
I thought that this was a great time to
um to do something and and so we
invented this whole initiative like
pretty much around Michael bow tie
creative built and maintains an entire
website for hannes free of charge he um
put my ideas into
actions and that made my my
job so much easier oh it's an initiative
that the four-person company is proud of
it's especially close to Perez's heart
because he himself has dyslexia I paved
my own path and that's why this this
this project means so much to me because
I want to help other people create their
paths bow tie creative is now helping
other people with mental and physical
challenges build websites across North
America all because of Michael Haynes
he's a great guy and it's fantastic
working with him and I can't wait to see
what happens next for him if you know um
any anyone that has a mental or physical
disability that wants to become an
entrepreneur or you know needs to needs
help to get started in the right
direction definitely check out our
website Haynes hopes with the kind of
support offered by Perez and his team
more people will find the confidence to
reach their goals I have a challenge you
have a challenge they not a person the
life with that
challenge I'm
my challenge is more pronounced that
than yours Robin Crawford Global News
Colona okay so we are back uh just
wanted to say so yeah if you know people
in the community uh that have a
disability but you know are also at a
you know they're not in a in a position
where they can help themselves I
definitely want to get in talk or in
touch with them and see the way that my
company can help um I this is why I do
the hustle Zone to be honest I really
want to promote that aspect of it every
time an entrepreneur buys a website that
that gives money towards someone that is
living on wellfare you know that wants
to just get off of the system and want
that wants to become an entrepreneur and
make money for themselves so by not
mentioning what we do um by not
acknowledging what we're doing uh it's
doing a disservice to those that are in
need that that could definitely use this
service and you know we have a few
websites just sitting there doing
nothing you know few tokens that we can
give away um and and then we also
encourage entrepreneurs that's why you
want to do business with us because you
know when you get a website we donate a
free website to an entrepreneur with a
disability and that's huge right so
that's what I do on my free time you
know I could be out there drinking
whatever but I'm I'm building websites
for everyone and to to to to make sure
that everyone can have that opportunity
to make some money because we're in the
information age so either way and then
also hustle Zone fitness challenge if
you guys want to be a part of it please
go to the hustle Zone fitness challenge
and if you want to participate or
volunteer let me know and um if you want
to get onto the hustle Zone folks please
please like our page book sometime and
we'll get you on uh it would be nice to
see and hear your stories I love stories
so um make sure so we got Joshua
back so now we're at our second half of
the show and the first question I'm
going to ask you my friend what do you
like to do for
fun I love
baseball I love baseball um so I was I
was a college pitcher back at Fitchburg
State so I like watching baseball I like
playing baseball um to be honest
unfortunately I don't have enough time
for fun but you know that's what I do
like um I'm not going to lie I do like
watching a certain team on Sunday Sunday
afternoons usually um for the NFL man
I'm I'm a Tom Brady fan I hope that
doesn't detrack
followers um I'm a big fan of him and so
those are the two things I like to do
for fun you know I you know know I go I
try to go to church um to that's my
Sunday morning activity right there my
Sunday afternoon so I guess Sundays
would be my my most day off I guess um
but baseball and sports man okay Pepsi
or
Coke you're gonna call me crazy but I'm
gonna have to go with Pepsi Pepsi yeah I
like Coke too I mean I go either way
okay Michael or Prince I I've been
asking this question all week and I just
I'm just curious to hear people's
response I'm going have to go Michael I
mean honestly I'm a 1990s 2000 baby um
so I'm not as hip on some of those
musics but I definitely have to go with
Michael probably on that because I know
his music more awesome and what what
inspires
you what inspires
me one thing that really inspires me is
when I see others who are struggling um
particularly with like drug addiction
and I see them come out of it and live
just the most incredible massively
successful life man take gr Cardone for
instance he talks about he was a drug
addict as a young age and um I lrae lrae
is a hip-hop artist he was a drug addict
as a kid and Josh Hamilton he was a drug
addict I love hearing stories of people
who were able to get out of that that
hard like you know that stigma of
addiction and be able to make something
with their life now
what's your definition of
entrepreneurialism someone who's willing
to take whatever it takes and never give
up on building a Financial Freedom a
financial future built
upon you know a specific reason in life
so like they're why um a lot of people a
lot of people they try to start a
business and they don't realize how much
really work goes into it and then most
people give up most people give up
before they've even started to build a
business for their Financial Freedom or
their financial future and I consider
four aspects to be super important to
building Financial Freedom and financial
wealth it's Faith Family Health and um
money so not giving up man and and
building businesses regardless of the
hate that's there where will you be five
years from now uh definitely should be a
millionaire because that's my goal
you know I talk a lot about money
especially in my personal brand like
Josh san.com and um that's where people
can buy my book by the way is my website
they can sign up for the book launch I
should say which is February 17th but I
talk a lot about money in there and a
part of make a change Inc is financial
education for kids the reason I talk
about that is because money is such a
hated topic but that's because people
don't like it you know people think it's
evil when the truth is loving money is
what's evil you can you build a future I
mean there's nothing better in the world
and I haven't done this personally but I
know there's nothing better in the world
than if like my aunt or a brother uh
inlaw you know needs my help in their
health in in health circumstances I can
be there we don't have to worry about
health insurance covering her or um you
know building generational wealth so my
kids never have to experience what I may
have experienced as a kid um you know
money's I don't just want to have money
or be a millionaire for for riches and
Glory don't get me wrong I want to
provide for my family in the best ways
possible I want to um enjoy my life but
it's if it's surrounded by your purpose
life and your why on life um money's a
Good Thing Man and that's where I see
myself in five years yeah I mean when it
comes to money I think that a lot of
people have a really poor understanding
of what money is and what money can do
and there's a lot of things that people
think they need money for and there's a
lot of things that you don't need money
for you know heard you know I don't want
to start a business because I don't have
the money again you know it's uh it's a
fallacy to think that money is the only
way of exchanging right and you know
people the first thing that people think
when they get money is that I need to
save the money no you need to invest
your money you need to take that money
money's temporary yeah you got to take
that money now and put it into something
else and you need you need to take the
life of the money and put it into
something else the paper means nothing
to you it's it's not going to anything
until you put it into assets like what
you're doing with real estate and and
and whatnot right so like we just I
think that there needs to be more
financial literacy in schools um
absolutely they're not doing enough of
that and I think that like you know I I
would like to see more of that education
out there how how are you teaching in
terms of your children like what what
are your your lessons in in regards the
money most of my kids are young but two
of them are little babies but um
I try to first and foremost lead by
example um and then you know when times
come and opportunities come I definitely
teach a lot about money in my house like
have a good mindset on money you know we
can change the world with money you know
um one of my one thing that I talk a lot
about is everything everything is money
now I'm not saying life is defined by by
money I'm saying your my sweatshirt this
coffee my gas in my car this book
everything is technically some sort of
curen or money and when people can just
understand that I feel like it's easier
for people to understand money so I talk
I mean obviously investing is one of the
most important things that I talk about
in my house kids um I try to start off
at a younger age because again they're
still young but I'm still trying to
build build them for their future um I
consider really everything in some way
shape or form and not honestly to be an
investment so sometimes you're either
investing in something that's going to
give you a bad return you know let's say
you smoke cigarettes no offense to
anyone who does you know that's probably
a a bad investment unless you're selling
the cigarettes individually and somehow
making money on it or whatever I don't
know um or you know take my personal
brand you know none of my businesses
actually started off with money first
off I'll start with that so you don't
need money to start a business but
second off when you do start having
money whether it be through credit cards
or loans or um your own personal savings
account everything investment so when I
all the startup and time that I put into
josh.com or into to make a chain
it's all an investment um so figure out
when you're making life choices and when
you're making purchases in general you
know obviously we have to live we have
to eat food we have to pay for the
things that we got to pay for but you
know beyond our means um you know what
are you going to use your money for is
it going to be for something that's
going to build you somehow some way in
your future or is it going to be wasted
and if anything bring you back in life
yeah that's awesome man so uh thank you
so much for coming on to the show I know
like it's been a long time coming and
you were on the show before but it was
just the at the infancy stage of the
hustle Zone that was like when I
discovered that I can actually do this
like you know you were probably on one
of the the first two shows and um so I I
I wanted to get you on to talk to you
privately well not privately but you
know to have a more intimate
conversation because you know you know
you you have a lot of great things to
say so um I'm sure that a lot of people
now seeing this they want to follow you
they want to get access to your book
they want to buy so how how can they do
that so with the book um I'm doing a
launch party just a Lot Like Richard
trino did um it's going to be on
February 17th from 7 to midnight 7 to
midnight Eastern Standard Time and
people can sign up uh that way they can
show my the support for it on my website
at josh.com basically just putting in a
name and email so I can know who is and
who is dedicated to purchasing the book
and my goal with that is to become a
number one bestseller on Amazon so if
you guys could do that for me that would
be really awesome I definitely
appreciate that kind of support in that
aspect um as far as make change in
there's a lot of big things happening
this year um my wife's starting to take
a little bit of um of the range too so
that's going to help out a lot with
making this make a change ink thing
explode um but we have different
opportunities to make a change ink you
people can obviously give on a one time
basis on a monthly basis they can
purchase merchandise and that money goes
towards make a change in the nonprofit
organization 501c3 tax exempt and all um
but if people necessarily maybe they
don't have money um we also have
volunteer opportunities and Ambassador
opportunities and I'll briefly explain
that in a volunteer opportunity that
could be anywhere from helping at an
event to spreading the word on social
media to blogging for us to um reviewing
things and giving feedback like on
website content whatever it might be
there's that kind of volunteer
opportunities and then there's
Ambassador which is a volunteer
opportunity to that will help raise
money so that could be someone who maybe
they don't have the money but they want
to somehow contribute financially to
help us grow our
organization and they can help do
different fundraisers or sell
merchandise or sell tickets to events um
or whatever it may be so those are the
two volunteer opportunities and then
lastly I really really am excited about
this I just want to touch on it before
we we go into the next segment
make a change Inc is also so we have our
American side like where we help kids in
America or I guess Canada too Ryan if
you want to get involved yeah where
we're focused on just helping kids who
are like in a foster care system or in a
tough circumstance and we provide
memories and um education for them and
then we're going to have a global
international section which is going to
be our orphan committee which is totally
focused on raising money for mission
trips and for building orphan orphanages
in Kenya that's where we're going to
start building this thing um so we have
two segments we have our American SL I
guess Canadian side and then we'll have
our Global section where we're helping
thr world country so they're going to be
this it's all going to be make a change
but we're going to have two teams
heading and focusing on both directions
that way we can make an impact
everywhere that's amazing wow you're
you're pretty busy man got doing your
thing so the uh the time is up um that
is it for the hustle Zone and U so thank
you so much Joshua for coming on and uh
folks you guys need to follow him I mean
I'm look at the wrong camera folks you
need you need to follow him like cuz I
got a lazy eye and I didn't realize
until I had to show cuz then like you
know the lazy eyes like looking at one
camera when it's when two of the eyes
should be looking at the one camera oh
that's okay just we just bumped the
camera but that's okay um
so either way you guys want to follow
Joshua he is a like I said before he's
just a great guy and he has a lot of
great things going on and I'd be happy
to to help out in any way for make a
change uh because like I you know in my
past I was doing a lot of Youth
initiatives and projects so you know a
lot of that stuff is deep um deep rooted
deeply rooted for me so um anyways
Joshua thank you so much if you want to
put yourself on mute and then I'll talk
to you after the show and uh so so folks
you know um I I think that what you guys
need to understand is that it doesn't
matter where you grow up doesn't matter
how you grow up doesn't matter who your
parents are you know Joshua said it in
this interview is that it's all about
choices you know you have to be able to
make the choice that will benefit your
life you know and when you make a choice
I mean you can make a choice in in one
second but you know if you're not uh
willing to to change your life you're
you're you're never going to get to
where you need to go and you can't put
it off you can't be like H I'm going to
put it off tomorrow no start today just
do something
small you know do something
small uh Joshua wasn't lucky you know
just Joshua just believes in hard work
Joshua believes in you know in saving
people's lives and Jos jhua has a why he
he
knows eternally he knows why He's doing
this and I I'm not sure if it's with his
if it's the relationship with his mom or
the fact that his dad you know died of a
herin heroin uh overdose I don't know if
that's what fuels it but either way
where he's at now is amazing and I think
that his success now is fueling him to
even become that much more successful
and also the people around him are
seeing that success in themselves all
the youth that he's helping out so I
encourage you guys um to check him out
to follow him and to buy the book If you
you're looking to find I know one person
that follows my show and I know I'm
talking to you always asking me
questions about stuff you need to buy
Joshua's book you know double your
income change your life make make a
change you right isn't that fitting make
a change make a change inc.org check
Joshua out folks add yourself to the
hustle own group you want to book uh
book now share this post if you like it
and um you know and if you are wanting
to be a part of the fitness challenge I
you know just hit me up you know a lot
of people are not stepping up and that's
okay I didn't stop like Puff daddy says
Can't Stop won't stop uhuh uhuh you know
I'm not stopping right so you know
whether you guys like it or not it is
what it is cuz I take action so and you
can you you can too everyone does so um
into some capacity so anyway I like I
like this uh interview this was an
awesome interview thank you guys all for
showing up I'm just going to see if
there's any more comments before I shut
her down
um let's see see
here we still got uh yeah we still got
Henry in here and we got
um and then Richard said that was
powerful yeah this is this is amazing
Leon always comes in he's like
boom just one word boom so anyway thank
you guys so much